Register of the Susan Weissman Radio Broadcast Interviews
Hoover Institution Archives
- 1996
  - Powers Abet Ethnic Strife in Balkans (Weissman interviews Peter Hudis, in studio, on the effects of the ethnic struggle and of nationalistic feelings in Bosnia. Dr. Hudis is the author of Bosnia and Herzegovina -- The Achilles' Heel of Western Civilization. In this interview he presents an overview of the breakup of Yugoslavia), 29 March 1996 (Box 7)
  - Daniel Singer on Recent French Strikes (Daniel Singer, Paris correspondent for The Nation magazine, and Weissman discuss the importance of the recent strikes in France), 5 April 1996 (Box 7)
  - Disintegration of the Parliamentary System (H. Ticktin, editor of new book, The Ideas of Leon Trotsky, and Weissman discuss the erosion and crumbling of parliamentary system in a post-Cold-War era), 19 April 1996 (Box 7)
  - Technology and Anti-Technology (Carl Boggs, Department of Sociology at the University of California at Los Angeles and author of The Socialist Condition, and Ira Sohn, an economist and expert on the Far East, Join Weissman in a discussion on anti-technology), 26 April 1996 (Box 7)
  - U.S. Faces Global Economics Challenge (Robert Brenner, Director, Center for Social Theory and Comparative History, University of California, Los Angeles, and Weissman discuss the increasing international economic competition and its impact on the upcoming U.S. elections), 3 May 1996 (Box 7)
  - Russian Elections and Chechnia (Vibeke von Sperling, Danish-radio Moscow correspondent, and H. Ticktin discuss with Weissman the upcoming Russian elections and the cease-fire in Chechnia.), 7 June 1996 (Box 7)
  - Michael Urban on Upcoming Russian Elections (Michael Urban, Professor of Soviet Politics, Department of History, University of California at Santa Cruz, and Weissman discuss the forthcoming elections in Russia), 31 May 1996 (Box 7)
  - Russian Elections: Bosnia Pact Wanes (In an essay, Weissman holds that the differences between Yeltsin and Zyuganov are minimal: both are elitists and nationalists. Next, Geoffry White, a Los Angeles psychologist, discusses the trauma cases he has handled in Bosnia. Last, Noloni Lasiewicz, Executive Director of Lasiewicz Foundation of L.A., a humanitarian and human rights organization, talks on her Bosnian experiences and the Dayton Peace talks), 14 June 1996 (Box 7)
  - Political Theory and Practice (Weissman, Clare Spark, and Steven Eric Bronner, member of Rutgers' Political Science Dept, discuss the culture wars and bridging the gap between theory and practice), 21 June 1996 (Box 8)
  - L.A. Barrio Renewal Lags after Riots (Although Malibu and the Northwest area of Los Angeles have seen renewal after fires and earthquakes, the renewal of the Watts area is limited; L.A. riot scars remain. A pawnshop owner describes fading hopes for revival of area. ), 28 June 1996 (Box 8)
  - Two Views of Russian Election Results (Weissman discusses the results of the recent Russian election with Renfrey Clarke an Australian news correspondent stationed in Moscow, and Michael Urban), 5 July 1996 (Box 8)
  - The Trap of "Lesser Evilism" (The trap of voting for what is construed as the lesser of two evils (the Democratic and Republican party) is probed by Weissman, and David Finkel, editor of Against the Current Magazine), 12 July 1996 (Box 8)
  - Russian Elections: What Next? (Weissman, David Johnson, Information Director of the Center for Defense Information, Washington D.C., and David Mandel, University of Quebec at Montreal, discuss the meaning of Yeltsin's "comeback" win, the role of U.S. advisors in Moscow, and possible impacts on future directions of the former Soviet Union), 19 July 1996 (Box 8)
  - A Socialist Enclave in Venus, Florida (Weissman interviews Jacque Fresco, who is the prime mover in the establishment of a sustainable socialist society in the town of Venus, Florida), 16 August 1996 (Box 8)
  - Chechnia and Bosnia: The Wars Drag on (Weissman interviews Ned Walker, program in Soviet and post-Soviet Studies, University California at Berkeley on Chechnia and Naloni Lasiewicz, Institute of Los Angeles on Bosnia on the status of continuing wars in both countries), 23 August 1996 (Box 8)
  - Right Wing Gains in South Africa (H. Ticktin and Weissman discuss the current trends in South Africa in the light of apartheid end), 6 September 1996 (Box 8)
  - Oregon Socialists New Ballot Choice (Weissman and Chris Phelps, Asst. professor of History, University of Oregon at Eugene, discuss his candidacy for senator in Oregon on the Socialist Party ticket as an alternative to traditional "lesser of two evils" voting), 13 September 1996 (Box 8)
  - Russia Continues Slide into Chaos (H. Ticktin and Weissman discuss Russia's failing progress in the attempt to transform the government and its infrastructure into a "market economy" from its Soviet origins), 25 October 1996 (Box 8)
  - Future of U.S. Labor Is Dim (Weissman and Robert Fitch, former labor organizer and author of The Assassination of New York, discuss the superficial rhetoric about the "rebirth" of the workers' movement), 1 November 1996 (Box 8)
  - Digital Revolution: Bane or Boon? 8 November 1996 (Box 8)
  - Belgrade Report; USSR Retrospect (In a live report from Belgrade Weissman discusses the rapidly changing situation in Yugoslavia where the dictatorial regime of Slobodan Milošević appears to be on the brink of falling. In part 2, Weissman and Ali Javadi conduct a discussion consisting of a retrospective of the rise and the cause of the disintegration of the Soviet Union, 6 December 1996 (Box 8)
  - October Revolution Anniversary UCLA (Weissman, Ali Javadi, Bob Brenner), 7 December 1996 (Box 8)
  - Che Guevara: A Biography, 19 December 1996 (Box 8)
- 1997
  - Four Guests Discuss Yugoslavia Election. Huge Demonstrations Mark Growing Unrest. Ire against Rigged Results Is Growing against Slobodan Milošević, 3 January 1997 (Box 8)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy: Chaotic or Directed? (Weissman and Michael Cox, Professor of International Politics at the University of Wales and author of The Cold War - Superwar Without a Mission, discuss American policy following the end of the Cold War. Dr. Ali Javadi, UCLA, notes the significance of the oil workers strike in Iran), 10 January 1997 (Box 8)
  - U.S. Calls Shots on Peru Hostage Coup (James Petris, Professor of Sociology at State University of NY at Binghamton, and author of Neoliberalism and Class Struggle in Latin America, and Weissman discuss the Peru hostage crisis. Later, Borka Pavicevic, of the Center for Cultural Decontamination in Serbia, discusses the Serbian crisis from Belgrade), 17 January 1997 (Box 8)
  - Nike and Globalism; Bosnia Turmoil. Bill Resnick Fights Nike in Oregon, Borka Pavicevic on Bosnia Struggle, 24 January 1997 (Box 8)
  - 40 Years of FBI Harassment of Lawyer, 14 February 1997 (Box 8)
  - China After Deng; Race Prejudice (Stuart Schram, U of London emeritus, reserve Prof. at Harvard and author of some 10 books on Mao, discusses Deng Xiaoping's role in China's history. Loren Goldner and Weissman discuss the role of religion and the role of Spain in development of racial prejudice), 28 February 1997 (Box 8)
  - Peggy Seeger Talks and Sings on Women's Day, 7 March 1997 (Box 8)
  - Detroit Newspapers Lock-out Strikers (Knight-Ridder has two newspapers in Detroit. For more than a year strikers have been out to obtain a new contract. Knight Ridder locks out strikers, violating agreements and labor laws), 14 March 1997 (Box 8)
  - Chaos Deepens in Russia and Albania (Nicholas Pano, Professor of History at Western Illinois University at Macomb, author of a book on Albania, notes the background causes of extreme unrest in Albania. Michael Urban, discusses the deepening chaos in Russia as road to "market system" continues), 21 March 1997 (Box 8)
  - Legacy of Russian Revolution After 80 Years (Speakers: Weissman, Albert Glotzer, New York city, once a LDT sympathizer, Savas Michael Matsas, Alexander Buzgalin, Dept. of History University Moscow, and H. Ticktin, 30 March 1997 (Box 8)
  - Peace Hope Dims in Arab-Israel Strife (Ira Sohn, an authority on the Near East who lives in Los Angeles, and Weissman discuss the implications and reasons for the Arab-Israeli peace process), 4 April 1997 (Box 8)
  - A. Buzgalin et al: Russian Chaos Deepens (Weissman and Alexander Buzgalin, and others discuss the deepening chaos as Yeltsin makes new promises), 11 April 1997 (Box 8)
  - Israeli-Arab Peace Pact Crisis Looms (Weissman discusses the possible looming breakdown of the Palestinian-Israeli peace process with Ygal Arens, Israeli-born, past president of American Anti-Arab Discrimination League, and Monir Deeb, a Palestinian peace advocate), 18 April 1997 (Box 8)
  - Che Guevara Biographer Interviewed (Weissman interviews Jon Lee Anderson, author of Che Guevara - A Revolutionary Life (Grove Press) in connection with the 50th anniversary of his death. Author holds Guevara broke the mold of compromise and status quo and developed a new consciousness wherever he went), 25 April 1997 (Box 8)
  - The Sorry State of Education in U.S. (Weissman and Clare Spark, historian and author, discuss the education morass in the USA. Tribute is given to Ralph Bunche), 2 May 1997 (Box 8)
  - Labour Scores in UK; Sweat Shops in L.A. (Harry Brighouse, Department of Philosophy, University of Wisconsin, Madison, and Weissman discuss the possible outcomes of the Labour Party landslide in British elections. Then, Alessandra Moctezuma notes that sweatshop labor continues in Los Angeles and Southern California), 9 May 1997 (Box 8)
  - East Palo Alto. Revolution Sans Revolt. (Michael Levin, Stanford University, and Weissman discuss the movement to create a new entity, East Palo Alto, to overcome its "murder capital of the world" reputation. Weissman then interviews Blair Sandler on capitalism), 16 May 1997 (Box 8)
  - NATO Growth: Catastrophe in the Making?, 23 May 1997 (Box 8)
  - Michael Parenti: Blackshirts and Red, 30 May 1997 (Box 8)
  - Did Sirhan Sirhan Assassinate Kennedy?, 17 June 1997 (Box 8)
  - Leftward Trends in Europe, USA, 20 June 1997 (Box 8)
  - Ireland: When Will the Shooting Stop?, 18 July 1997 (Box 8)
  - Corporations Attack Academe, Tenure, 1 August 1997 (Box 8)
  - UPS Strikers Fight Union-Busting Ploy, 8 August 1997 (Box 8)
  - U.S. Writers of the 30s - 60s, 30 August 1997 (Box 8)
  - Mexico Politics Upset by Elections, 12 September 1997 (Box 8)
  - Women's Lib. Progress Ebbs, 19 September 1997 (Box 8)
  - Isaac Bashevis Singer: A Complex Writer, 26 September 1997 (Box 9)
  - Powers Abet Indonesia/Timor Genocide, 3 October 1997 (Box 9)
  - Experts Dissect Global Market Crash (H. Ticktin and Ira Sohn, economics expert in Los Angeles, join Weissman on analysis of the causes and effects of the recent major global market crash), 31 October 1997 (Box 9)
  - China's State Capitalism Breeds Chaos, 7 November 1997 (Box 9)
  - Lady Reporter Describes Chaos in Russia, 14 November 1997 (Box 9)
  - Post Gulf War U.S. Strategy Questioned, 5 December 1997 (Box 9)
  - Korea's Kim Dae Jung Now Faces IMF, 19 December 1997 (Box 9)
  - Ethnic Cleansing, Bosnia War [note: no tape available; recording tape broke], undated (Box 9)
- 1998
  - Ron Carey's Teamsters Abet Sweatshops, 2 January 1998 (Box 9)
  - Iran and Algeria: What Next for Islam?, 9 January 1998 (Box 9)
  - Globalization: Is Marxism Dead?, 23 January 1998 (Box 9)
  - Women: 50s-90s...Russian Women Today, 6 March 1998 (Box 9)
  - Serbs Continue Albanian Ethnic Cleansing, 13 March 1998 (Box 9)
  - Russian Crisis; Clinton Visits Africa, 27 March 1998 (Box 9)
  - Latin America Love in Time of Hate and Indonesia: Repression Increases, 3 April 1998 (Box 9)
  - Documentary Film Maker and Russian Chaos, 10 April 1998 (Box 9)
  - Russia Sinks into New Economic Morass, 24 April 1998 (Box 9)
  - 150th Anniversary of the Communist Manifesto, 1 May 1998 (Box 9)
  - Globalization: Latin America, China, 8 May 1998 (Box 9)
  - Yugoslavia Crises Escalate, 5 June 1998 (Box 9)
  - Russia Crisis Deepens; Irish "Peace"? (Renfrey Clark, veteran Australia correspondent in Moscow, sees little hope for ebbing of Russian economic chaos. Then Michael Cox, University of Wales Dept. of International Politics, Aberystwyth, feels recent peace pact in Ireland may hold), 12 June 1998 (Box 9)
  - L.A. Workers Protest Welfare Cuts, 19 June 1998 (Box 9)
  - Jewish Impact on World's Ethics (Weissman interviews Thomas Cahill on his new book The Gift of the Jews: How a Tribe of Desert Nomads Changed the Way Everyone Thinks and Feels), 26 June 1998 (Box 9)
  - London and L.A. Homeless Now Publish Papers, 3 July 1998 (Box 9)
  - Puerto Rico Strike; Chiapas Unrest, 10 July 1998 (Box 9)
  - L.A. Bus Riders Protest Poor Service, 17 July 1998 (Box 9)
  - The Decline and Fall of Post-USSR Russia, 24 July 1998 (Box 9)
  - The GM Strike: Outcome and Implications, 4 August 1998 (Box 9)
  - Humor Not Dead in Post-USSR, 11 August 1998 (Box 9)
  - Russian Economy Nears Meltdown, 18 August 1998 (Box 9)
  - Mike Davis on The Ecology of Fear (Mike Davis, author of City of Quartz, discusses his new book, The Ecology of Fear on the flawed development of Southern California), 25 August 1998 (Box 9)
  - Democracy Stumbles in Russia, Chile, 15 September 1998 (Box 9)
  - Asian Flu or World Capitalism Crisis?, 29 September 1998 (Box 9)
  - Serbs Continue Slaughter in Kosovo, 6 October 1998 (Box 9)
  - Memorial Service for Mark Sharron, 10 October 1998 (Box 9)
  - Pinochet in UK: Will Justice Prevail?, 27 October 1998 (Box 9)
  - Four Scholars Discuss Market Socialism, 3 November 1998 (Box 9)
  - Floods Bring Misery to Latin-America, 17 November 1998 (Box 9)
  - Economic and Political Crises Continue in Japan and Indonesia, 24 November 1998 (Box 9)
  - Mike Davis: L.A.'s Feet of Clay, 2 December 1998 (Box 9)
  - U.S. Abandons UN in New Near East Politics (tape missing), 11 December 1998 (Box 9)
  - Russian Liberal Assassinated. What Next?, 15 December 1998 (Box 9)
  - Iraq and Iran: Near East Peace Falters, 22 December 1998 (Box 10)
  - 150 Years of the Communist Manifesto, 23 December 1998 (Box 10)
  - Russian Economy Sinks Lower and Lower, 29 December 1998 (Box 10)
- 1999
  - Clinton: Impeachment for Wrong Reasons?, 12 January 1999 (Box 10)
  - Yugoslavia in Chaos; "Market" Economy Falters, 19 January 1999 (Box 10)
  - Global Market Economics: Boom or Bust?, 26 January 1999 (Box 10)
  - Russian Politics, Economics Hit New Low, 16 February 1999 (Box 10)
  - NATO-U.S. Kosovo Peace Plan Falters Anew, 23 February 1999 (Box 10)
  - Afghanistan Women Enslaved by Taliban, 2 March 1999 (Box 10)
  - Elia Kazan: Saint or Sinner?, 16 March 1999 (Box 10)
  - Ethiopia-Eritrea War Surfaces Anew and NATO Kosovo Bombing Angers Russia, 23 March 1999 (Box 10)
  - NATO Bombs Serbia: War Is on in Kosovo, 30 March 1999 (Box 10)
  - Movie: "A Place Called Chiapas,", 6 April 1999 (Box 10)
  - D. Singer: "Their Millennium or Ours?,", 13 April 1999 (Box 10)
  - Mark Cooper Interviews Noam Chomsky, 18 April 1999 (Box 10)
  - Four Experts Discuss Kosovo Crisis, 20 April 1999 (Box 10)
  - Black-"Red" U.S. Politics 1918-1930s, 27 April 1999 (Box 10)
  - Whither Kosovo Now?...Loach on Film, 27 July 1999 (Box 10)
  - Iran Turmoil; Puerto Rico Seething, 3 August 1999 (Box 10)
  - Russia: The Continuing Crisis Deepening, 10 August 1999 (Box 10)
  - New Book Labor Betrayed by Leaders, 17 August 1999 (Box 10)
  - Post-War Serbia: What Next? and Russia: What Next After Yeltsin?, 24 August 1999 (Box 10)
  - Russian Money-Laundering Scandal and The Fear of Old Age Perils, 7 September 1999 (Box 10)
  - Hollywood Biz: A Humorous Look, 21 September 1999 (Box 10)
  - Chechen War Flares Anew and New Book on Old Age Discussed, 5 October 1999 (Box 10)
  - Democracy Founders in Chile and Slaughter Resumes in Chechnia, 8 November 1999 (Box 10)
  - The Prison-Industrial Complex, 15 November 1999 (Box 10)
  - The WTO: Labor's Friend or Foe?, 22 November 1999 (Box 10)
  - Russians Blast Chechnia and Labor Blasts World Trade Organization, 29 November 1999 (Box 10)
  - Torture Flourishes in "Democracies,", 6 December 1999 (Box 10)
  - Police Gas, Jail 600 WTO Protesters, 13 December 1999 (Box 10)
  - Duma Elections: A Democratic Farce, 20 December 1999 (Box 10)
  - Columbia Truce Faltering and University Students Discuss Activism, 27 December 1999 (Box 10)
- 2000
  - Three Experts Discuss Russia's Future, 3 January 2000 (Box 10)
  - Green Party Candidate Speaks and Two Experts: The Assault on Children, 10 January 2000 (Box 10)
  - Three Experts Discuss Russia's Destiny, 17 January 2000 (Box 10)
  - Einstein's Daughter and Cuban Boy, 14 February 2000 (Box 10)
  - Discrimination Against Women and Whither Pinochet Now?, 21 February 2000 (Box 10)
  - FBI vs. Lennon; Iran Election; Deaths Haunt Chechnia, 28 February 2000 (Box 10)
  - L.A. Police Scandal...Pinochet Returns, 6 March 2000 (Box 10)
  - Chilean Elections...Russian Humor, 13 March 2000 (Box 10)
  - Ticktin on Russian "Elections" and Working Women Today, 20 March 2000 (Box 10)
  - Russian Election Results and Muhammad Ali's Greatest Fight, 27 March 2000 (Box 10)
  - Who Owns America? And Labor's Hoffa Sells Out Anew, 3 April 2000 (Box 11)
  - L.A. Hotel Workers Living Wage Strike and Russia: Putin's Crooked Election, 10 April 2000 (Box 11)
  - Global Fight Against Globalism and Stock Market Convulsions: Why?, 17 April 2000 (Box 11)
  - Elian's Release...IMF and WB Protests, USA-Cuba Relations: What Next?, 24 April 2000 (Box 11)
  - The Global Rise of Anti-Capitalism, 1 May 2000 (Box 11)
  - Playwright Zinn Says Marx Is Still Alive, 8 May 2000 (Box 11)
  - Putin's "Strong State" and Sweatshops Still Thrive in L.A., 19 June 2000 (Box 11)
  - The Taliban Terror against Women, 26 June 2000 (Box 11)
  - Election Upset in Mexico and A New Biography of Marx, 3 July 2000 (Box 11)
  - Iran's Islamic Rule Slowly Ebbs and A New Book on American Labor, 10 July 2000 (Box 11)
  - Kosovo Today and Workplace Conflicts, 17 July 2000 (Box 11)
  - The Democrats Convene in Los Angeles, 11 August 2000 (Box 11)
  - Background Briefing, 13 August 2000 (Box 11)
  - Cohen, Kozol, and Urban Assess the Los Angeles Democratic Convention, 21 August 2000 (Box 11)
  - Chile Coup Anniversary; AIDS Cases Rise, 11 September 2000 (Box 11)
  - L.A. Strike; Death Penalty; Wen Ho-Li, 18 September 2000 (Box 11)
  - L.A. Strikes End; Kozol Backs Gore as Best Lesser Evil for Education, 23 October 2000 (Box 11)
  - Soviet Return to Capitalism Becomes a Catastrophe, 30 October 2000 (Box 11)
  - Five Experts Dissect U.S. Elections, 6 November 2000 (Box 11)
  - Media Election Coverage Poor at Best, 13 November 2000 (Box 11)
  - Gore? Bush? and Hoover's Merry Pranks, 4 December 2000 (Box 11)
  - Labor Organization in S. California and Mexico Greets Fox, 18 December 2000 (Box 11)
- Program lists and article, 1995-2000 (Box 11)